# Richa Kaur

# **Business Analyst**

Business-minded analyst with a demonstrated ability to deliver valuable insight via data analytics and advanced data driven methods from 2+years. Particularly relied on mathematical and technological background to attain a meaningful solution . Good technical experience in solving complex business problems using data and implementing machine learning algorithms.

Rourkela, Odisha

© (+91)9090302071

https://richakbee.github.io/richabudhraia8@gmail.com

richabudhraja8@gmail.com

https://github.com/richakbee

https://www.linkedin.com/in/richakaur-931500141/

### **EDUCATION**

- BTech in Computer Science &
   Engineering (with Honors), 9.1 CGPA
   BPUT, Odisha- 2019
- St. Josephs Convent School, Rourkela (1995-2013), 90 % in X, 89% in XII

### **SKILLS**

- Tools & Framework Python3, R, SQL, Tableau, MS office ,Jupyter , Tensorflow, keras, sklearn,AutoML pandas,Pycaret,Flask,flutter, Aws/Azure/GCP,MongoDB, Snowflake ,PowerBI
- Techniques Regression, Classification, Clustering, Bagging, Boosting, Dimensionality Reduction, Hyper Parameter Tuning, Data Visualization, Exploratory Data Analysis, Data Mining, Feature engineering, Data Wrangling, Web Scraping, ANN, CNN, RNN (basic), NLP (basic), Transfer Learning, Deployment, Advanced Data Analytics.

### **COURSES & CERTIFICATION**

- <u>Deep Learning Specialization</u> Coursera.
- <u>DeepLearning.Al TensorFlow</u>
   <u>Developer Specialization</u>,
   Coursera.
- Applied Data Science in Python
   Specialization ,University of Michigan
- <u>Descriptive Statistics with R</u>,IIT Kanpur , NPTEL
- Data Mining , IIT Kharagpur ,NPTEL
- Intro to Statistics , Udacity
- Intro to Descriptive Statistics, Udacity
- Intro to Inferential Statistics ,Udacity
- Hands On Tableau A-Z, Udemy
- Tableau Advanced ,Master Tableau for Data Science , Udemy
- Machine Learning , Stanford University.

### **AWARDS**

 Scholarship awardee for being top of the batch in 2<sup>nd</sup>,3<sup>rd</sup>,4<sup>th</sup> 5<sup>th</sup> semester.

# **STRENGTHS**

- Excellent Oral &Written communication
- Committed to Lifelong Learning
- Ability and interest in working in a fastpaced, ambiguous and rapidly changing environment.

# **HOBBIES**

- Fitness : Yoga ,Strength Training @gym
- Adventure: Hiking , Trekking , Camping
- Book Reading: (atleast 10 pages / day)
- Sports: Carrom, Chess, Badminton (award Wining), Cycling 10-15 km everyday

# WORK EXPERIENCE Swiggy

**Business Analyst** 

April 2021- Present

# Roles & Responsibilities :-

- Working for Growth and product analytics of Instamart (swiggy's grocery delivery service)
- Working in collaboration with Product managers & Business teams to leverage swiggy's food platform for expansion of Instamart to multiple cities (Currently 5+ cities)
- Leveraging Click Stream Data analysis, A/B testing for Performance of Banners, customer target marketing, Visitors profiling, Improvement of Search mapping system.

# NMTechnosol (with @Affine Analytics ) Business Analyst

July 2019 -April 2021

# Roles & Responsibilities : -

- Performed descriptive analysis and provide self-service analytical solutions to strategy global heads of pharma section of a Fortune 10 animal health company.
- •Implemented Initial EDA deck and Visualization Dashboard to understand data behavior.
- Performed Advanced analytics, & querying to Derive insights from data.
- •Served various on-site adhoc analytical requests , hypothesis testing .
- Developed fully automated reports from concept to product in form of Dashboard (creation, maintenance and story telling with Tableau.)
- ■Identified KPI for waterfall analysis for bulk purchasing potential of customers.
- •Segregated Customers into Loyal ,Switch & new category & Performed Repeat purchase analysis to identify potential loyal customers to improve sales..
- Developed requirements and create requirements documents and process flows.
- Data Science Initiative : (Clustering & analysis for target marketing)
  - o Collaborated with different domain experts to ideate & derive initial KPI's.
  - o Aggregated Transactional level data to perform in detailed exploratory analysis.
  - o Derived insights & Performed dimensionality reduction using factor analysis.
  - Used K-means ++ for Clustering & identified 4 clusters in data.
  - Visualized Clusters using PCA & performed cluster analysis to generateinsights.

#### **Mindfire Solutions**

January 2019 -June 2019

### Full Stack Web Developer (Intern)

# **Roles & Responsibilities :-**

- Created a Blogging Site from scratch where users can follow people, see posts from them, write, edit, delete their own posts.
- Worked on Bug tracking web app, used by Team Members to assign aBug Handling job to a particular Member, Track the Status of the Bugs

# PERSONAL LEARNING AND PROJECTS

- <u>Sentiment Analysis</u>—Worked on a Classification problem to understand sentiment hidden in text & classify if it is positive or negative. (on IMDB moviereviews).
- <u>Back Order Prediction</u> End to End ML application to detect if a product could come short & Order has to be cancelled.(inventory management)
- Big Mart Sales End to End ML application deployed on GCP to predict the sales of an item at a particular Outlet.
- Insurance Fraud Detection End to End ML application deployed on Azure to detect if the insurance claim is fraudulent or genuine.
- Image Classification Web app -A Flask Object Segmentation app that classifies between cats & dogs images when uploaded by a user. (CNN)
- <u>Digit Recognizer ( A deep learning app on flutter )</u> A its a Deep Learning app that recognizes Digits . Users have Two options : either upload an image of a digit or draw the digit on drawing space. CNN Model was created in TensorFlow. ...
- <u>Demand Forecasting (Bike Sharing & Rental)</u> A Regression problem to forecastthe numbers
  of bikes to be rented at any hour of a day .(Kaggle challenge).